

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A passionate Full Stack software developer. Experienced in building web apps with JavaScript / Angular / Reactjs / Nodejs and other interesting libraries and frameworks. Focused on decentralization technologies such as messaging, microservices and microfrontend.

SKILLS

- System design
- Web application development
- Gather technical requirements
- System documentation
- Research

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer, F3 Capital, Feb 2022 - Current

Worked with development of new technologies using CBSE (Component Based Software Enginnering).

- Documented style guidelines to keep the design consistent across the team and created an enterprise user interface library.
- Documented code changes in manuals and presentations to orient developers.
- Collaborated with teammates to improve processes and produce better tools.
- Developed web applications using Agile and continuous delivery processes to refine quality and improve output.

Full Stack Developer, Santander, Sep 2021 - Feb 2022, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais

- Recommended and developed security measures in post-implementation analysis to reduce risk of breach.
- Developed the 'Open Banking' module.
- Improved Implementation of user experience tracking in loan operations.
- Analyzed project requirements, translating specifications into functional application components.
- Escalated issues and concerns to facilitate resolutions and avoid impacts to timelines.

Junior .Net Developer, Rumo Soluções, Jan 2021 - Feb 2022

- Employed varied front-end technologies during development, including Asp.Net, Angular and more.
- Developed Webcrawling solutions implementing renowned software design patterns such as Factory, Decorator and Template .
- Participated in project meetings with other technical staff, business owners and subject matter experts.

Software Developer Intern, **Rumo Soluções**, Jan 2019 - Dec 2021, Lagoa Santa, Minas Gerais

- Learned correct tools and processes for different types of development to minimize errors and achieve coding goals.
- Moved between different projects and project teams and applied knowledge to contribute to objectives.
- Coordinated documentation of software updates.

Fullstack Developer, Interligados Tec, Aug 2021

- Developed program logic for new applications based on fresh coding, and also revamped logic from existing applications.
- Participated in end-to-end website development.
- Developed architectural solutions such as project templates for new websites.
- Developed a UI Library for the company.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Systems Analysis and Development

Jun 2022

FACISABH - Faculdade de Ciências Sociais Aplicadas BH.

Transferred to Unicesumar

Bachelor of Science, Systems Analysis and Development

Jun 2022

Unicesumar - Lagoa Santa, Minas Gerais

WEBSITES AND SOCIAL LINKS

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jackson-pires-ramalho-58a2a080

Portfolio: https://metalefs.github.io/react-portfolio/?lang=EN_US